Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Score Collection, circa 1940-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Additional scores received after original processing was completed, circa 1900-2016, VII; Item 149-185
  - Berger, Arthur, 1912-2003 Partita, piano Partita 1947, 1 manuscript score (10 pages); 36 cm (Box 17, Item 175)
    Manuscript (Ozalid copy)
    At end of score: N.Y. Oct. 1947
    Inscribed to Leo Smit.
    Contents: Intonazione -- Aria -- Capriccio -- Intermezzo -- Serenade.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Fantasy, piano Piano fantasy New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1957, 1 score (45 pages); 31 cm (Box 17, Item 176)
    Marked by Leo Smit for performance.
    Bears inscription from Copland to Leo Smit.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Quartets, piano, strings Quartet for piano and strings New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1952, 1 score (36 pages) and 3 parts; 31 cm (Box 17, Item 177)
    Score and parts bear performance markings.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Symphonies, no. 3 Third symphony New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1947, 1 score (155 pages); 27 cm (Box 17, Item 178)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Variations, piano Piano variations New York: Cos Cob Press, reissued under the auspices of Arrow Music Press, 1932, 1 score (16 pages); 28 cm (Box 17, Item 179)
  - Haieff, Alexei, 1914-1994 Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1; arranged Concerto for piano and orchestra: reduction for two pianos New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1954, 1 score (65 pages); 31 cm (Box 17, Item 180)
    Bears inscription from Haieff to Leo Smit.
  - Johnson, Pete, 1904-1967 Piano music. Selections 5 boogie woogie piano solos New York: Leeds Music, 1941, 1 score (24 pages); 31 cm (Box 17, Item 181)
    Bears inscription from Johnson to Leo Smit.
    Contents: Blues on the downbeat -- Cherry red -- Holler stomp -- Kaycee on my mind -- Roll 'em Pete.
  - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1903-1978 Contrastes et developpements: pour piano Berlin: Edition russe de musique, 1938, 1 score (18 pages); 33 cm (Box 18, Item 182)
    Bears inscription from Nabokov to Leo Smit.
  - Raksin, David Laura. Laura; arranged Laura: theme melody form the 20th Century-Fox picture "Laura": a composition for piano New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1945, 1 score (5 pages); 32 cm (Box 18, Item 183)
    Bears inscription from Raksin to Leo Smit.
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 Selections Bound volume of five compositions by Igor Stravinsky 1924-1929, 1 bound volume; 33 cm (Box 18, Item 184)
    Contents: Sonate pour piano (1925) -- Sérénade en la en quatre mouvements pour piano (1926) -- Concerto pour piano suivi d'orchestre d'harmonie, réduction pour deux pianos (1924) -- Capriccio pour piano et orchestre en 3 parties, réduction pour deux pianos à 4 mains (1929) -- Apollon musagète: ballet en deux tableaux, réduction pour piano à 2 mains(1928).
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 Collection of twelve compositions by Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky and Igor Stravinsky compiled by Leo Smit undated, 12 scores (Box 18, Item 185)
    Held together by notebook rings.
    Contents: Wiegenlied in Sturm; O pain, O pleasure (op. 6 no. 3); Humoresque; Album leaves, op. 19 no. 3; op. 51, no. 4; In the village, op. 40 no. 7; Winter evening, op. 54 no. 7; Serenade, op. 63 no. 6; Peasant plays the accordion, op. 39 no. 12; Evening reverie, op. 19 no. 1; Scherzo humoristique, op. 19 no. 2; None but the lonely heart, op. 6 no. 6; Danse russe, op. 40 no. 10 / Tchaikovsky -- Danse russe, from Petrushka, for two pianos; Divertimento for violin and piano / Igor Stravinsky.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Composers--New York (State)--Buffalo; Music--Manuscripts; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999
Genres
Scores
Associated Material
Additional Guides
All scores by Leo Smit (Series I) in the collection are cataloged in WorldCat and are available in BISON, the online catalog for the University at Buffalo Libraries, by performing a "Title begins with" search under "Leo Smit Score Collection".
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Leo Smit Papers, 1939-2000
Mus. Arc. 6.2
A small collection of personal documents, writings by Smit, correspondence (chiefly photocopies of letters from Aaron Copland to Smit), clippings, programs, and lecture materials.
Leo Smit Photograph Collection, circa 1926-1999
Mus. Arc. 6.3
A collection of photographs of and by Leo Smit, with digital images online.
Remembering Leo Smit (1921-1999)
An online exhibit commemorating the life and career of Leo Smit. It contains many images of Smit as well as photographs taken by him. A list of Smit's compositions, compiled by the composer, is also included.
Related Resources Outside the Music Library
Guide to the Leo Smit Papers, 1905-1998
JPB 00-42
Finding aid for the collection at the New York Public Library for the Performing Arts. Music Division. The Leo Smit collection contains scores, correspondence, and research materials.